Register of the Wilfrid Bade Papers, 1927-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Wilfrid Bade Papers
1927-1945
48019
Bade, Wilfrid, 1906-
11 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (4.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Manuscripts of writings, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and photographs, relating to dissemination of German propaganda during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Germany. Reichsministerium fur Volksaufklarung und Propaganda.; Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; National socialism.; Propaganda, German.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; Germany.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1927-1943, 1945. (Box Boxes 1-7)
  Correspondence, arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically by name of correspondent within each year.
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929
  - 1930
  - 1931
  - 1932
  - 1933
  - 1934 (Box 2)
  - 1935 (Box 3)
  - 1936
  - 1937 (Box 4)
  - 1938 (Box 5)
  - 1939
  - 1939 (Box 6)
  - 1940
  - 1941
  - 1942
  - 1943 (Box 7)
  - 1945
  - undated
- SUBJECT FILE. (Box Boxes 7-11)
  Memoranda, reports, manuscripts, typescripts, notes, clippings, etc., arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Articles (Box 7)
  - Aufstellung
  - Auslands Presse, roster of foreign correspondents, May 1944
  - Bills, cash receipts, tickets, etc.
  - Catholic Clergy Subject to Punishment (Box 8)
  - Clippings
  - Deutsches Nachrichtenbüro, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Dresden Bank (Box 10)
  - Die Dynastie Karadjordjevic und das Jugoslawische Volk
  - Films
  - Fragen Eines Preussischen Militaristen
  - Gewerbebank zu Höhr
  - Koenig Alexander I der Vereiniger
  - Die Kunst
  - Novel written by W. Bade
  - Same (Box 11)
  - Nationalsozialistische Deutsche Arbeiterpartei (NSDAP). Partei-Kanzlei (M. Bormann), 1941, 1943-44
  - Poems by W. Bade
  - Sage Mir Was Liebe Ist
  - Die Schlacht in Polen
  - Zug ins Reich
  - Miscellaneous
- Photographs, circa 1939-1944 (Box 48019 Envelope)
  10 photos depicting WWII Germany with special emphasis on the Hitler Youth Movement